Preliminary Inventory of the Adam Joseph Galinski Papers, 1945-1971
Hoover Institution Archives
Adam Joseph Galinski Papers,
1945-1971
78057
Galinski, Adam Joseph, 1896-1973
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, personal documents, writings, photographs, and printed matter, relating to conditions in Soviet forced labor camps, and to twentieth century Polish history and culture.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Forced labor--Soviet Union.; Poles--United States.; Political prisoners--Soviet Union.; Poland.; Poland--History--20th century.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); United States.
Container List
- Certificate of release from the Soviet Labor Camp Vorkuta. Original and English translation, 1956 (Box 1)
- Personal papers, military decorations
- Letters to the family from Vorkuta Camp, 1948, 1954
- Fragments from unpublished memoirs, including Vilna Region under German occupation, 1942-1944
- Diary of Jadwiga Galinska, Rome-Washington, 1945-1955
- Correspondence, 1946-1955
- Correspondence with Polish authorities concerning emigration to the United States, 1958-1961
- Correspondence with the United Nations Office of the High Commissioner for Refugees, 1963-1967
- Testimony before the Congressional Committee on Un-American Activities: "Soviet Justice," life in the Soviet Labor Camps, 1960 April
- Congressional hearing: "Soviet espionage through Poland," testimony of Colonel Pawel Monat, 1960 June
- Three interviews of Radio Free Europe about life in the Soviet Labor Camps, 1946-1956, New York, 1960 August-September
- Speeches and writings. Life in Soviet labor camps, Washington, 1960
- Eastern provinces of Poland under Soviet domination; methods of subjugation, 1939-1941, 1944-1945, New York, 1960
- Correspondence with Polish Emigre Publishing Houses in Europe (Box 2-3)
  - Polish Research Center (polski Osrodek Naukowy), London
  - Polish Cultural Foundation (Polska Fundacja Kulturalna), London
  - "Veritas," Catholic Publishing Center, London
  - Polish Veterans Bookstore (ksiegarnia S.P.K.), London
  - Polish Publishing Houses and Bookstores: "Orbis," "Gryf," "Odnova"
  - Polish Library in Paris (Ksiegarnia Polska w Paryzu)
  - Polish Literary Institute, Paris
  - Jozef Pilsudski Institute of America, New York
- Catalogues and correspondence with subscribers in the United States, 1968-1971
- News from Poland, weekly bulletin of Free Europe Committee, New York, 1961-1964, 1966-1967 (Box 4)